我想向你展示一些我从未被记录过的演讲中的例子。
I wanna show you some examples from a talk I gave that never got recorded.
我认为这很酷。
And I think this is kinda cool to see.
而不是我坐在屏幕前把所有这些都写出来，
Instead of me sitting here at a screen and writing all these out,
我只是要指出一些实际的用例。
I'm just gonna point out some actual use cases.
所以在这里，我们有 getAppAlerts，对吗？
So here, we have getAppAlerts, right?
和 getDirectMessages。
And getDirectMessages.
它们都返回警报数组和 JSON 之类的消息。
They're both returning the arrays of alerts and messages like JSON.
我实际上可以将所有这些承诺和回应结合起来。
And I can actually just combine all those promises, responses.
在纯函数设置中，您将使用任务而不是承诺。
In a pure functional setting, you'd be using task instead of promise.
只需说 concat，我们就可以轻松地在 promise 上编写 concat
We can easily write concat on promise by just saying concat
无论这个承诺持有什么，无论那个人持有什么。
whatever this promise is holding with whatever that one's holding.
然后，我们能够组合两个 API 调用和
And then, we get the ability to combine two API calls and
get 可以收集他们所有的结果。
get can collect all their results.
我们能做到这一点。
We can do that.
它是关联的，并且是封闭的，因此我们可以并行执行此操作。
It's associative, and it's closed, so we can do that in parallel.
我们可以把它分块，我们可以一次访问一堆服务器
We can chunk it, we can hit a bunch of servers at once and
带着所有的结果回来。
come back with all the results.
映射减少。
MapReduce.
同样，我之前没有提到这一点，
In the same vein, I didn't mention this earlier,
但 map 是一种定义半组或对象的方法。
but map is a way to define a semi-group or on a object.
它的工作方式是，如果你看这里，我们会得到一个帖子。
And the way it would work is if you look here, we’re gonna go get a post.
我们在核心函数式编程课程中做了这个例子，我们
We did this example on the hardcore functional programming class where we
去从服务器上得到一个帖子，我们把它拿回来了，然后
went and got a post from the server, we got it back, and
然后我们从服务器收到评论，我们想将它们分配给帖子。
then we got comments from the server and we wanted to assign them to the post.
嗯，这就是一行。
Well, this is going that in one line.
getPost 将 JSON 作为地图实例返回，对吗？
getPost returns JSON as a map instance, right?
所以这就像 map 是一个对象，它将合并为一个 concat。
So it's like map is an object and it will merge as a concat.
如果它在某个键上遇到合并冲突，它只会合并合并冲突。
And if it hits a merge conflict on a key, it'll just concat the merge conflict.
所以你最终得到的是这种地图合并情况，我们
So what you end up having is this kind of map merge situation where we
只需通过调用 concat 即可为我们的博客文章分配评论。
just assigned comments to our blog post just by calling concat.
每个人都看到它是如何工作的吗？
Does everybody see how that works?
我的意思是，我只是有点想看看这些小例子。
I mean, I'm just kinda gonna glaze over a bunch of these little examples.
但如果你问我和其他人，这非常有用。
But it's pretty useful if you ask me and everyone else.
所以这是一个tryCatch。
So here's a tryCatch.
我们在核心函数式编程课程中看到了这一点。
We saw this in the hardcore functional programming class.
我们要读取文件同步。
We're gonna read file sync.
公平地说，这并不纯粹，但是
This isn't pure, to be fair, but
它显示了我们要说的 readFileSync 的例子。
it shows the example of we're gonna say readFileSync.
它只会将所有内容与完整地图连接在一起。
And it's gonna just concat all their contents here with the full map.
它会读取所有这些文件并连接所有内容，太棒了。
It'll read all these files and concat all the contents, awesome.
如果它们中的任何一个爆炸，我们就从左边走。
And if any of them blow up, we will just get the left.
我没有那个例子。
I don't have that example.
它只会告诉你错误。
It'll just show you the error.
正如我们之前看到的，
And as we saw before,
我们可以用另一种类型包装，以优雅地做出不同的决定。
we can wrap either in another type to kinda gracefully make different decisions.
所以这里是同样的事情，异步，几乎没有任何变化，对吧？
So here's the same thing, async, and almost nothing changes, right?
我们刚才说promisify读取文件，既然我们在这里说promise，
We just said promisify the read file, and since we're saying promise here,
它有一个 concat 方法，它会做完全相同的事情，但异步。
it has a concat method, it will do the exact same thing, but async.
除了我提供给它的幺半群或半群之外，我没有改变任何东西。
And I changed nothing other than the monoid or semi-group I provided it with.
而且你可以看到空的，它只是 Promise.resolve 空字符串。
And you can see the empty, it's just Promise.resolve empty string.
因此，我们在这种情况下有一个幺半群，空字符串和一个承诺
So therefore, we have a monoid in the situation, empty string, and a promise
持有空字符串将是此特定工作流程的空方法。
holding empty string would be the empty method of this particular workflow.
在这里，让我们看看，读取一个文件并获取一个数组。
Here, we have, let's see, read a file and get an array.
与字符串的工作方式完全相同。
Works the exact same way as the strings.
它只会组合所有数组。
It'll just combine all the arrays.
这是进行空检查的示例。
Here's an example of doing a null check.
所以现在，我们正在串联这些东西，对吧？
So now, we're cascading these things, right?
我们说好的，我想进去，我想读取所有这些文件，异步。
We're saying okay, I wanna go in there, I wanna read all these files, async.
我想得到他们所有的内容，我想把它们分成几个词。
I wanna get all their contents, I wanna split them into words.
所以我们有所有这些数组，我要连接所有这些数组。
So we have all these arrays, I'm gonna concat all those arrays.
但如果我得到一个空值，我只想停下来。
But if I get a null, I just wanna stop.
[笑] 否则，一切顺利，一切都很好。
[LAUGH] Otherwise, everything worked out and everything's good.
那是强大的。
That's powerful.
这就是力量。
This is power.
[笑] 所以让我们再看几个例子，然后我们将构建一些东西。
[LAUGH] So let's see couple more examples, and then we'll build some stuff.
在这里，我们获得了一堆配置并将它们从文件中组合起来。
Here, we have getting a bunch of configs and combining them from files.
这是一个很好的。
Here's a good one.
所以这是一种典型的用例。
So this is kind of a typical use case here.
所以我们要做的是遍历 DOM 树。
So we're gonna do is we're gonna walk over the DOM tree.
我做了一个树函子斜线可折叠的幺半群。
I made a tree functor slash foldable monoid.
我所做的是说我的报告是一张地图，它会得到元素计数。
And what I've done is say my report is a map, and it's gonna get the element count.
这是在玩弄这样一个事实，如果我是一个类型并且我完全持有
And this is playing off the fact that if I'm a type and I'm holding entirely
幺半群，那么我可以连接，因为我所有的部分也是幺半群。
monoids, then I can concat just because all my pieces are also monoids.
那么地图所做的只是合并，对吗？
So what map does is just merge, right?
如果它击中相同的键，它将合并这些作为合并冲突解决方案。
And if it hits the same key, it combines those as the merge conflict resolution.
所以它要做的是遍历整个 DOM 树
So what it's gonna do is run through the entire DOM tree and
获取每个元素、每个类名、每个标签和最大值。
get every element, every class name, every tag, and max.
而且每一种都有不同的组合方式，并且
And each one has a different way to combine, and
它将在整个树的一个循环中给我一份完整的报告。
it will give me an entire report in one loop over the entire tree.
哪个规则[笑]，对吧？
Which rules [LAUGH], right?
我已经为 DOM 树处理做过几次不同的事情。
I've done this a few different times for DOM tree processing.
如果我们想要超级花哨，如果我有一堆文件和
And if we wanna get super fancy, what if I have a bunch of documents and
我想折叠那个列表并获得关于它的报告？
I wanna fold down that list and get reports on that?
还有一层，对吧？
There's one extra layer, right?
我不只是在做一个 DOM 树，我现在正在做整个网站并得到一份报告
I'm not just doing one DOM tree, I'm doing the entire site now and getting a report
在所有元素、类、标签和边界 regs 的最大高度上。
on all the elements, classes, tags, and the max height of the bounding regs.
所以，再次，超级强大。
So that is, again, super powerful.